Guide to the Zilkha Gallery and Center for the Arts Gallery Exhibition Catalogs Collection, 1973 - [ongoing]
Zilkha Gallery and Center for the Arts Gallery Exhibition Catalogs Collection, 1973 - [ongoing]
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Ezra and Cecile Zilkha Gallery.
1000-48
1.75
4
The Center for the Arts (CFA) gallery was renamed the Ezra [Wesleyan class of 1947] and Cecile Zilkha Gallery in the fall of 1982 in honor of a gift from The Zilkha Foundation, Inc. The Gallery features contemporary art installations as well as faculty and student work.
This collection includes exhibition catalogs from the CFA and Zilkha Galleries. Also included are exhibition announcement cards, postcards, and mailings.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Periodically transferred from the Center for the Arts.
Historical Note
Wesleyan’s Center for the Arts (CFA) complex of buildings, designed by Kevin Roche, John Dinkeloo and Associates, opened in 1973. One building was designed as a new gallery space, known as the CFA galleries, to be dedicated primarily to contemporary art and student works. After construction, the gallery was occasionally divided into two separate exhibition spaces, known as the CFA North and CFA South galleries. This space augmented the university’s Davison Art Center gallery, whose focus was primarily on printmaking and photography. The CFA gallery was renamed the Ezra [Wesleyan class of 1947] and Cecile Zilkha Gallery in the fall of 1982 in honor of a gift from The Zilkha Foundation, Inc.
Collection Overview
This collection includes exhibition catalogs from the CFA and Zilkha Galleries. Also included are exhibition announcement cards, postcards, and mailings.
Collection Arrangement
Arrangement is chronological.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Ezra and Cecile Zilkha Gallery.; Art--Exhibitions.
Related Material
Archival vertical files collection – Center for the Arts (for gallery ephemera and clippings).
Exhibition posters are shelved separately as part of the archives’ Broadside Collection.
Davison Art Center Exhibition Catalogs Collection, 1952-[ongoing], collection 1000-21.
Davison Art Rooms Exhibition Catalogs Collection, 1928-1949, collection 1000-45
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - Exhibition announcements and postcards, 1973- (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Alexander Calder: Tapestries. January 31 - March 1, 1975
      2 copies.
    - E. E. Cummings - Paintings and Drawings. March 3-23, 1975
    - The Gregorian Collection: Antique Oriental Rugs of the Great Silk Route from Chinese Turkestan to Anatolia. September 6 - October 19, 1975
    - Sculptors and their Drawings: Selections from the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden. January 23 - February 29, 1976
    - American Art in the Making: Preparatory Studies for Masterpieces of American Painting, 1800-1900. July 3 - August 1, 1976
    - Contemporary Clay: Ten Approaches. October 29 - December 5, 1976
    - Jeff Silverthorne - Photographs. February 22 - March 10, 1977
  - 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Women of the World War One Poster. January 28 - February 24, 1981
    - Robert Ferris - Paintings on Paper. May 6 - June 12, 1983
    - Contemporary Landscape Painting. August 24 - October 23, 1983
    - Cindy Sherman. November 9 - December 16, 1983
    - Large Drawings. January 26 - March 9, 1984
    - A Writer's Eye: An Exhibition of Field Study Drawings by Paul Horgan. January 26 - March 9, 1984
    - Furniture, Furnishings: Subject and Object. [1984]
    - Offset: A Survey of Artists' Books by Gary Richman. [Early fall 1985]
    - Claude Garache - Prints 1965-1985. October 17 - November 24, 1985
  - 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Kunst als Kultur/Art as Culture: Recent Art from Germany. August 27 - October 19, 1986
    - Italo Scanga. Recent Sculpture and Drawings. October 30 - December 10, 1986
    - The Female Form as Muse: Sculpture by Nancy Bowen. January 21 - March 6, 1987
    - Daniel Buren: Metamorphoses--Works in Situ. November 5 - December 11, 1987
  - 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Modern Redux: Critical Alternatives for Architecture in the Next Decade. January 20 - March 6, 1988
    - Franz Erhard Walther. August 31 - October 28, 1988
    - David Deutsch. New Work. May 3-27, 1989
    - Kiki Smith. May 4 - June 25, 1989
    - Rotraut, [Günther] Uecker, [Yves] Klein. August 30 – October 29, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Exotism. (jointly with) Art of Incorporation: Transition in the Arts of Africa and Oceania. January 23 - March 9, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Eve Andree Laramee: The Eroded Terrain of Memory. (The Broken Mirror: Part One). September 25 - October 28, 1990
    - Jessica Stockholder: Untitled Seepage. (The Broken Mirror: Part Three). January 29 - March 3, 1991
    - Astrid Klein. May 7 - June 9, 1991
  - 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Multiple Exposure: The Group Portrait in Photography. January 21 - March 6, 1992
    - Mary Kelly: Gloria Patri. March 6 - April 8, 1992
    - Otto Kunzli: Oh, Say! May 5 - June 7, 1992
    - Keiji Shinohara: Woodblock Prints May 13 - December 18, 1992
    - James Hyde. May 4 - June 6, 1993
    - Concrete Jungle: Mark Dion, Alexis Rockman, Bob Braine. October 15 - December 10, 1993
  - 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Composition Décomposition: Philippe Deléglise and Roland Dahinden. April 19 - May 29, 1994
    - re:Visioning the Familiar. August 30 - October 2, 1994
    - Songs with a Dying Fall: Works on Paper and Canvas by David Schorr. October 25 - December 9, 1994
  - 1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Decter, Joshua and Andrei Roiter. An Inside-Out Life: The Conversation as Fiction. 1995
    - Andrei Roiter: Potato Head. January 17 - March 5, 1995
    - Laughter Ten Years After. October 31 - December 9, 1995
  - 1996-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mark Morrisroe: My Life. Polaroids 1977-1989. January 16 - March 2, 1996
    - Dissolving Landscapes: Photographs by Jungjin Lee. April 30 - May 26, 1996
    - Glenn Ligon: Day of Absence. April 23 - May 30, 1997
    - Ann Messner: Flood. April 29 - June 1, 1997
    - Amazon of the North: James Bay Revisited. September 2 - October 19, 1997
    - Tony Feher: Siempre Contigo. October 29 - December 14, 1997
    - Figuring the Body: Nancy Bowen & Nancy Davidson. January 21 - March 1, 1998
    - Peter Waite: Social Studies. April 22 - May 31, 1998
    - Embedded Metaphors. September 1 - November 2, 1998
    - Elana Herzog: The Carpet Paradigm. November 8 - December 13, 1998
    - Beverly Semmes: Not Here. September 1 - October 24, 1999
  - 2001 - [ongoing] (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Looking Forward, Looking Black. January 24 – March 4, 2001
    - The Alumni Show: In Celebration of the Thirtieth Anniversary of the Center for the Arts, Wesleyan University. November 1 – December 7, 2003
    - Robert Taplin: The Five Outer Planets. January 22 – February 29, 2004